Like in the functional safety concept,
就像前面功能安全概念中我们所做的
we will now allocate technical safety requirements to the system architecture.
现在我们把技术安全要求纳入我们的系统架构中
The first three technical safety requirements we
我们会把前三个技术安全要求
identified will be allocated to the LDW safety software component.
放在我们的 LDW 软件安全组件中
Let's summarize what these three safety requirements are doing.
我们来总结一下这三个安全要求完成的工作
The LDW safety software element receives
LDW 安全软件元素从基础车道保持功能块中
the vibrational torque request from the basic lane keeping functionality block.
获取震动扭矩请求
The LDW safety element checks to make sure that
然后 LDW 安全软件元素检查请求
the torque request is below the maximum amplitude and frequency.
确保其值小于最大幅度和频率值
If the maximum amplitude or frequency is crossed,
如果请求值大于限定值
the LDW safety element deactivates the functionality and sets the torque request to zero.
LDW 安全软件元素会忽略该请求并将扭矩请求值设为0
The LDW safety block then sends
然后 LDW 安全块把存储的请求数据
its stock request to the final EPS torque generator block.
发送给最终的 EPS 扭矩生成块
A warning light needs to alert the driver to the malfunction.
报警灯会闪烁 提示司机有故障
The LDW safety block will send a status signal out to the car display.
然后 LDW 安全模块会发送状态信号到车辆的显示模块
The signal indicates whether or not
信号用来提示是否
the lane assistance item is active and functioning properly.
车道辅助系统处于活动状态且工作正常
The status signal would also go to the final EPS torque generator block.
状态信号也会进入最终 EPS 扭矩生成模块
This block could use the status signal as
该模块使用状态信号做附加检测
an extra check on sending an invalid signal to the motor.
以决定是否发送无效信号到引擎
To check the validity and integrity of the torque request,
为了检测扭矩请求的正确性和完整性
a softer block would be added specifically for this task between
在 LDW 安全块和最终 EPS 扭矩生成块之间
the LDW safety block and the final EPS torque generator block.
我们会专门放一个软件模块
This block is ensuring that the signal has not been corrupted during the transmission.
该模块确保信号在传输过程中没有损坏
For the memory test requirement,
对于内存检测要求
there is a separate external block with the code.
我们用一个分离的外部代码块来实现
This block will run when the vehicle is turned on
因为车辆上的各个 ECU 并不能集成这个代码块
because the ECUs throughout the vehicle can't share this block.
所以在车辆启动时 我们会运行它
The ASIL for the functional blocks are inherited from the technical safety requirements.
各功能模块的 ASIL 从技术安全要求中得出
You can see that safety relevant blocks are labeled ASIL C,
大家可以看到 这些安全相关模块被标为 ASIL C
except for the memory test code,
除了内存检测代码块
which we previously explained only needs to be labeled ASIL A.
我们前面讲了 内存检测模块需要被标为 ASIL A
The basic lane assistance functionality is labeled QM,
基础车道辅助功能被标为 QM
which we discussed in the previous lesson in reference to ASIL decomposition.
这个我们在上一课中讲 ASIL 分解时提到过
We have now derived technical safety requirements and allocated them to the architecture.
现在 我们已经得出各个技术安全要求 并已经把它们放在我们的架构中